ZACK POLLARD

1 The Pyghtle, Westoning, MK45 5LJ github.com/zackpollard \diamond git.zackpollard.pro

Mobile: 07928015705 \$\precede \text{Email: z.r.e.pollard-14@student.lboro.ac.uk}

PROFILE

A Loughborough University graduate with a 1st class BSc in Computer Science and 1-year experience as an intern at IBM iX, the worlds largest digital agency. Systems Administrator and Programmer with 9 years of experience, through both freelance work and employment. Primarily works using Java with varied experience in other languages including C++, Python and Node.JS.

EDUCATION

Loughborough University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (1st Class)

Dissertation: Secure Smart Lock System

Harlington Upper School

GCSE and Sixth Form

· A Levels: Mathematics (A), Physics (B), ICT (C)

· Level 3 BTECs: Subsidiary Diploma in Sport (Distinction*)

September 2009 - July 2014

Harlington, Bedfordshire

September 2014 - July 2018

Loughborough, Leicestershire

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM - iX Studios London

Interactive Developer

July 2016 - November 2016 Southbank, London

- · Received the top performance rating during placement, awarded to only 10% of interns, allowing application back to IBM without interview as a graduate.
- · Worked on internal projects utilising Node. JS as the backend to provide easy to use, RESTful APIs.
- · Working directly with clients from Deutsche Bank and BP.

· Deutsche Bank:

- Built a custom development pipeline using Jenkins 2.0 for the Deutsche Bank teams paving the way to increased productivity and automation.
- Onboarded a new team onto the Deutsche Bank project whilst operating as the technical lead on-site for IBM.
- Used Jenkins 2.0, Groovy, Docker and Git

BP

- Worked within an agile team, both local and remote to produce a premium B2C Android application released globally.
- Designed and implemented a custom solution for making a single Android application for multiple different markets with the same source code.
- Reinvented the devops flow using Jenkins pipelines to automate adding new modules, source code merging, releases, unit testing and more, along with feedback in case of code issues.
- Wrote dynamic view generation code for Android, allowing us to create receipts populated by each module individually so we didn't need unique receipts code for every country.
- Used RxJava, Retrofit, Java, Git, Gradle and Jenkins 2.0

Woodlands Middle School

Assistant Systems and Network Technician

July 2011 and July 2012 Flitwick, Bedfordshire

- · Kept to a schedule and completed jobs within required deadlines.
- · Problem solving under pressure in time-sensitive situations.
- \cdot Worked effectively with members of a team to coordinate network repair tasks to prevent downtime.

Freelancing 2009 - Present

Java Development and Systems Administration

- · Dealing with clients requirements on a daily basis.
- · Managing time and providing accurate time frames for completion of projects.
- · Working as part of a team on projects utilising git for version control.

KEY SKILLS

- · **Problem Solving:** Used extensively during my time at IBM, one example was when we needed to re-write the Android application to work in different countries with some code being slightly modified. We worked on building a custom solution so that we could have individual modules that could be put into any application, and the code would adapt itself based on what modules were loaded when the application started up.
- · Communication: During my time at IBM I worked with clients on and off-site, as well as having to communicate effectively with remote teams during stand-ups and throughout the day. During my freelance work, I had to continually communicate with remote clients to keep them up to date with progress and establish requirements.
- · Teamwork: Demonstrated throughout my time at IBM, specifically due to working in small agile teams on both the Deutsche Bank and BP projects. Whilst on the Deutsche Bank project I was given the opportunity to be the technical lead, part of which involved onboarding a new team.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Languages Java, C++, Python, Lua, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Node.JS, Groovy

Data Structures XML, JSON, YAML

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools Git, Jenkins, LaTeX, KVM, SSH, Docker, Google Cloud, RxJava, Retrofit

Operating Systems CentOS 6/7 (Redhat), Debian, Arch (Arch), UnRAID, Cisco IOS

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

SaxophoneABRSM Grade 8PianoABRSM Grade 6Music TheoryABRSM Grade 5

Kayaking & Canoeing Canoe England BCU 2 Star

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- · Played the Saxophone and Piano for 13 and 15 years respectively.
- · Participated in various bands throughout Middle and Upper School, as well as playing in the University Jazz band, Tuxedo Swing.
- · Kayaking, Canoeing, Mountain Biking and Rock Climbing for 8 years.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.